{"name": "C01 2020-07", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The parallelogram below has consecutive angles with measures x\u00b0 and 25\u00b0. What is the value of x?", "choices": {"A": "100", "B": "115", "C": "130", "D": "140", "E": "155"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. A retail sales associate's daily commission during 1 week was $30 on Monday and Tuesday and $70 on Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday. What was the associate's average daily commission for these 5 days?", "choices": {"A": "$50", "B": "$51", "C": "$54", "D": "$55", "E": "$56"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. \n\nWhat is the greatest common factor of 45, 50, and 84 ?\n", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. For what value of x is the equation  2(x - 12) + x = 36  true?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "16", "D": "20", "E": "30"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. A bag contains exactly 22 solid-colored buttons: 4 red, 6 blue, and 12 white. What is the probability of randomly selecting 1 button that is NOT white?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. On a map,  inch represents 12 actual miles. Two towns that are 5 inches apart on this map are how many actual miles apart?", "choices": {"A": "120", "B": "60", "C": "30", "D": "24", "E": "12"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Caden had exactly 45 plants to sell. After Day 1 of his sale, he had exactly 42 plants left. After Day 2, Caden had exactly 39 plants left. After Day 3, he has exactly 36 plants left. Assuming Caden will continue to sell plants at that daily rate, how many of these plants will he have left at the end of Day 6?", "choices": {"A": "33", "B": "27", "C": "24", "D": "6", "E": "3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. An on-demand movie service charges $5 per month, plus $2 for each movie rented. Which of the following equations models the relationship between M, the number of movies rented per month, and T, the total monthly cost, in dollars, for the service?", "choices": {"A": "M = 5 + 2T", "B": "M = 2 + 5T", "C": "T = 5 + 2M", "D": "T = 2 + 5M", "E": "T = (5 + 2)M"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. What are the solutions to the quadratic equation  (2x + 5)(3x - 4) = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "-5 and 4", "B": " and ", "C": " and ", "D": " and ", "E": " and "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. An 8-inch-by-6-inch rectangle is cut along a diagonal to form 2 triangles. What is the area, in square inches, of each triangle?", "choices": {"A": "7", "B": "12", "C": "14", "D": "24", "E": "48"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. In a class of tenth graders, no student participated in more than 1 of the following extracurricular activities;  the class played in the band;  sang in the chorus;  played football; and  played basketball. What fraction of the class did not participate in any 1 of these 4 activities?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. What is the smallest integer greater than \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "7", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "31"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. In \u25b3ABC shown below, sin C = and the length of AB is 6 inches. What is the length, in inches, of AC\uff1f", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. The table below shows the first 5 terms of an arithmetic sequence. Which of the following is a general expression for the nth term?", "choices": {"A": "2n - 1", "B": "3n - 2", "C": "4n - 3", "D": "5n - 4", "E": "6n - 5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. What is the perimeter, in feet, of the figure shown below?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "62", "C": "70", "D": "80", "E": "84"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Manuel  estimates  that  of a pizza is left. Stephen estimates that 3/4 left. They are going to compromise for a joint  estimate by using the number halfway between their 2 estimates. What is their joint estimate?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. So far this basketball season, Sherita made 46 of her first 60 free throws, giving her a free-throw average of about 76.7%. What is the minimum number of free throws she would need make from now on in order to have a free-throw average of at least 80%?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "10", "D": "14", "E": "20"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Two function are defined as f(x) = 2x - 1 and g(x) = x\u00b2 + 1 . Which of the following expressions represents f(g(x))?", "choices": {"A": "x\u00b2 + 2x", "B": "2x\u00b2 + 1", "C": "2x\u00b2 + 2", "D": "4x\u00b2", "E": "4x\u00b2 - 4x + 2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. Data Set A consists of the 8 numbers listed below. Data Set B consists of the 8 numbers in A and a 9th number, which is greater than 90. How will the mean and the median of B compare to the mean and the median of A?        62, 76, 76, 80, 82, 87, 94, 96", "choices": {"A": "The mean and the median of B will each be greater than the mean and the median of A.", "B": "The mean and the median of B will each be less than the mean and the median of A.", "C": "The mean and the median of B will each be the same as the mean and the median of A.", "D": "The mean of B will be the same as the mean of A, and the median of B will be greater than the median of A.", "E": "The mean of B will each be greater than the mean of A, and the median of B will be the same as the median of A."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. A truck traveling at 35 mph has a leaky radiator that is losing 4 fluid ounces per minute. How many miles will the truck travel before the radiator, which held 480 fluid ounces when it began to leak, is empty?", "choices": {"A": "13.7", "B": "17.5", "C": "35.0", "D": "70.0", "E": "120.0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the midpoint of the line segment that has endpoints (-5, 8) and (3, -1)?", "choices": {"A": "(-2, -9)", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "(8, -9)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  The ordered pairs (x, y) in one of the following tables belong to a linear function. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. In \u25b3ABC shown below, m\u2220A = x\u00b0 , m\u2220B = (2x)\u00b0 , m\u2220C = (3x)\u00b0 , AB = c inches, AC = b inches, and BC = a inches. Which of the following inequalities correctly relates the side lengths of \u25b3ABC?(Note: m\u2220A denotes the measure of \u2220A, and AB denotes the length of AB. The triangle is NOT drawn to scale.)", "choices": {"A": "a &lt; b &lt; c", "B": "a &lt; c &lt; b", "C": "b &lt; a &lt; c", "D": "c &lt; a &lt; b", "E": "c &lt; b &lt; a"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. What is the slope of the line that passes through (1, 5) and (17, 7) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The     perimeter     of    a    particular    rectangle    is 36 centimeters. The longer sides or the rectangle are each 2 centimeters longer than each of the shorter sides of the rectangle. What is the length, in centimeters, of one of the longer sides of this rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "9", "C": "10", "D": "18", "E": "32"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Use the following information to answer question 26-28.Winter  Fun  Ski  Resort sells  only  2 types  of  tickets\u2014adult and student. On  Monday, the  resort sold 200 tickets, 1 ticket to each skier. Of those tickets, 25 were sold to first-time skiers. When Alyssa skis the resort's main run, her elevation, E feet, at any point on the run is modeled by the equation  where t is the number of seconds after she begins skiing at the star t of the main run.26. The resort collected a total of $6,000 in ticket sales on Monday. The price of an adult ticket is $50 and the price of a student ticket  is  $25.  How many  adult  and student tickets were sold on Monday?", "choices": {"A": "adult:40    student:160", "B": "adult:80    student:120", "C": "adult:100    student:100", "D": "adult:120    student:80", "E": "adult:160    student:40"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer question 26-28.Winter Fun Ski Resort sells only 2 types of tickets\u2014adult and student. On Monday, the resort sold 200 tickets, 1 ticket to each skier. Of those tickets, 25 were sold to first-time skiers. When Alyssa skis the resort's main run, her elevation, E feet, at any point on the run is modeled by the equation  where t is the number of seconds after she begins skiing at the star t of the main run.27. On Monday,  the resort  sold 1 ticket  to  each  of   the 8 members of the  Herzog  family. Assume this  family  is a representative sample of all of the skiers at the resort on Monday. How many of the 8 members  of the Herzog family are NOT first-time skiers?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer question 26-28.Winter Fun Ski Resort sells only 2 types of tickets\u2014adult and student. On Monday, the resort sold 200 tickets, 1 ticket to each skier. Of those tickets, 25 were sold to first-time skiers. When Alyssa skis the resort's main run, her elevation, E feet, at any point on the run is modeled by the equation  where t is the number of seconds after she begins skiing at the star t of the main run.28. What is Alyssa's elevation, in feet, at the start of the main run?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "300", "C": "3,000", "D": "30,000", "E": "300,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. One side of square ABCD has a length of 18 meters. A certain rectangle whose area is equal to the area of ABCD has a width of 6 meters. What is the length, in meters, of the certain rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "24", "C": "27", "D": "30", "E": "54"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. The 2 x 2 matrices A and B below are related to matrix C   by   the   equation   C = 2A - 3B.   What   is matrix C?          ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Jen is doing an experiment to determine whether a high-protein food affects the ability of  white  mice to find their way through a maze. The mice in the experimental group were given the  high-protein  food; the mice in the control group were given  regular food. Jen then timed the mice as they found their way through the maze. The table  below shows the results.The average time tile mice in the experimental group took to find their way through the maze was how many seconds less than the average time taken by the mice in the control group?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "11", "C": "13", "D": "16", "E": "19"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. In the United States, phone numbers begin with a 3-digit area code. Now, there are  restrictions  on some of the digit, but in the future, as more and  more  area codes arc needed, the restrictions may need  to  be  lifted. If, and when.  there  are  no  restrictions  and each or the 3 digits can be any integer from 0 through 9, how many area codes will be possible?", "choices": {"A": "27", "B": "30", "C": "720", "D": "729", "E": "1,000"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. The function y = 2 sin(8\u03c0x) is graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. How  many  x-intercepts does the graph of this function have on the interval 0 &lt; x &lt; 1 ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "7", "D": "8", "E": "9"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. If   both x  and  are  positive  integers,    what  is the least possible value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "21", "B": "27", "C": "36", "D": "63", "E": "189"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer question 35-38.In parallelogram ABCD shown below, the diagonals intersect at E, m\u2220BDC = 42\u00b0, m\u2220BDA = 71\u00b0, and AB= inches.(Note: The figure is NOT drawn to scale; m\u2220PQR denotes the measure of \u2220PQR.)35. What is m\u2220BAD?", "choices": {"A": "23\u00b0", "B": "42\u00b0", "C": "48\u00b0", "D": "67\u00b0", "E": "71\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Use the following information to answer question 35-38.In parallelogram ABCD shown below, the diagonals intersect at E, m\u2220BDC = 42\u00b0, m\u2220BDA = 71\u00b0, and AB= inches.(Note: The figure is NOT drawn to scale; m\u2220PQR denotes the measure of \u2220PQR.)36. Given that  inches, what is the value of n?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": " 6", "D": " 12", "E": "36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Use the following information to answer question 35-38.In parallelogram ABCD shown below, the diagonals intersect at E, m\u2220BDC = 42\u00b0, m\u2220BDA = 71\u00b0, and AB= inches.(Note: The figure is NOT drawn to scale; m\u2220PQR denotes the measure of \u2220PQR.)37. Suppose A and C are located at (2, 10) and (30, 3), respectively, in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. What are the coordinates of E ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following information to answer question 35-38.In parallelogram ABCD shown below, the diagonals intersect at E, m\u2220BDC = 42\u00b0, m\u2220BDA = 71\u00b0, and AB= inches.(Note: The figure is NOT drawn to scale; m\u2220PQR denotes the measure of \u2220PQR.)38. Which of the following triangles is congruent to \u25b3ABE?", "choices": {"A": "\u25b3ADC", "B": "\u25b3AED", "C": "\u25b3BCE", "D": "\u25b3BCD", "E": "\u25b3CDE"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Which of the following expressions is equal to  for all positive real numbers a and b?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The  track  for a  model   railroad  display  is  set  up   as 2 circles that are tangent to one another and have diameters of 30 feet and 50 feet, respectively, as shown below. The engine of the train travels at a constant rate of 75 feet per minute. To the nearest minute, how many minutes does the engine take to go in a figure 8 pattern around the entire track exactly 1 time?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "7"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. =\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. What is the value of the positive real number x such that  ?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "50", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The points (-4, -5), (0, -3), and (6, 0) lie on a line  in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. Which of the following points also lies on that line?", "choices": {"A": "(-3, -4)", "B": "(-1, -4)", "C": "(1, -2)", "D": "(4, -1)", "E": "(9, 1)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Rya and Sampath start running laps from the same starting line at the same time and in the same direction on a certain indoor track. Rya completes one lap in 16 seconds, and Sampath completes the same lap in 28 seconds. Both continue running at their same respective  rates  and  in  the  same  direction  for 10 minutes. What is the fewest number of seconds after starting that Rya and Sampath will again be at their starting line at the same time?", "choices": {"A": "88", "B": "112", "C": "120", "D": "220", "E": "448"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The CFO of Math King Enterprises estimates that if the company sets a price of c cents for each unit  of their new product, then the weekly profit from selling the produce will be modeled by p(c) = 1,600c - 4c\u00b2, where 0 \u2264 c \u2264 400. According to this model, for which of the following values of c will the weekly profit for this product be the largest?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "40", "C": "100", "D": "200", "E": "400"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Given consecutive positive integers a, b, c, and such that a &lt; b &lt; c &lt; d, which of the following expressions has the greatest value?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The ratio of the perimeters of two squares is 2:3. If the area of the larger square is 324 square feet, what is the length, in feet, of the side of the smaller square?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "18", "C": "24", "D": "27", "E": "36"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. What is the set of all integer solutions for the inequality  ?", "choices": {"A": "{3, 4, 5}", "B": "{2, 3, 4, 5, 6}", "C": "{2, 3, 4, 5}", "D": "{1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}", "E": "{1, 2, 3, 4, 5}"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Wind blowing against a flat surface exerts a maximum force equal to kSv\u00b2, where S is the area of the surface, v is the wind's velocity, and k is a constant. If a 40 mile-per-hour ( mph ) wind can exert a maximum force of 50 pounds on a 1-square-foot flat surface, what is the maximum force, in pounds, that an 80 mph wind can exert on a 2-square-foot flat surface?", "choices": {"A": "100", "B": "128", "C": "200", "D": "400", "E": "1,600"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Roger will pour concrete to make a sidewalk with the dimensions, in feet, shown in the figure below. He will pour the concrete to a depth of 4 inches. One bag of concrete mix makes 0.6 cubic feet of concrete. What is the least whole number of bags of concrete mix that Roger needs in order to make the sidewalk?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "44", "C": "50", "D": "58", "E": "67"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Radius OA of the circle shown below is perpendicular to AP. The circle intersects OP at B. The length of AP is 12 centimeters, and the measure of \u2220APO is 20\u00b0. Which of the following values is closest to the length, in centimeters, of BP \uff1f(Note: sin 20\u00b0\u2248 0.342, cos 20\u00b0\u2248 0.940, and tan 20\u00b0\u2248 0.364)", "choices": {"A": "2.1", "B": "4.4", "C": "6.9", "D": "7.6", "E": "8.4"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. The average of 10 test scores is x. When the highest score and lowest score are removed from the 10 scores, the average is y. Which of the following is an expression for the average of the highest score and lowest score? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Which of the following is the solution set of ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Each face of 2 cubes with faces numbered from 1 through 6 has a  chance of landing up when the 2 cubes are tossed. What is the probability that the sum of the numbers on the faces landing up will be less than 6? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. At 2:00 p.m., Louisa leaves Kansas City in her car traveling east on I-70 toward St. Louis at an average speed of 68 mph. At precisely the same time, Antonio leaves St. Louis in his car traveling west on I-70 toward Kansas City at an average speed of 57 mph. The driving distance from St. Louis to Kansas City is 240 miles. At what time, to the nearest minute, will they drive past each other on I-70 ?", "choices": {"A": "3:46 p.m.", "B": "3:50 p.m.", "C": "3:53 p.m.", "D": "3:55 p.m.", "E": "4:06 p.m."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. There are 10 points in a plane, and no 3 of the points are collinear. These 10 points, taken 2 points at a time, determine how many distinct lines? ", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "20", "C": "35", "D": "45", "E": "90"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The expression n! (read as n factorial) is defined as the product of all positive integers up to and including n, whenever n is a positive integer. For example, 4! = 1 \u00b7 2 \u00b7 3 \u00b7 4. Whenever n is a positive integer, which of the following is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "120", "C": "2", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. Which of the following must be true for each set of 4 consecutive positive integers?l. \tAt least 1 of the 4 integers is prime.II. At least 2 of the 4 integers have a common prime factor.III. At least 1 of the 4 integers is a factor of at least 1 of the 3 other integers.", "choices": {"A": "l only ", "B": "ll only", "C": "l and Ill only", "D": "ll and III only", "E": "I, II, and III"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. When  is expanded and like terms are combined, what is the coefficient of  ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "4", "E": "6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. A hill makes an angle of 20\u00b0with the horizontal,, as shown below. A taut guy wire, AB, extends from the base of the hill, point A, to point B on a vertical pole. Point B is 25 ft directly above where the pole is inserted into the ground at point C. Given that the length of AC is 60 ft, which of the following expressions represents the length, in feet, of the guy wire?(Note: For a triangle with sides of length a, b, and c that are opposite angles \u2220A, \u2220B, and \u2220C, respectively, == and - 2ab cos \u2220C.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}]}